<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>A collection of paintings and limnings, by the best masters: will be sold by auction on Friday the 1st of November, 1689. at Tom's Coffee-House, in Pope's-Head-Alley, over against the Royal-Exchange, Cornhil The sale beginning precisely at three of the clock in the afternoon. Catalogues of which are destributed by Mr. Gilliflower, in Westminster-Hall: Mr. Nott in the Pall Mall: Mr. Bently in Russel-street, Covent-Garden: Mr. Wilkinson in Fleet-street: Mr. Hargrave, at the Kings-Head, over against Furnivals-Inn in Holborn: Mr. Miller, at the Acorn, in St. Paul's Church-yard: and Mr. Crouch over against the Royal-Exchange, in Cornhil, booksellers. The conditions of sale as usual, and the time of paying and fetching away the lots so bought, to be within three days after it, at the said place.</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1689</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 10 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 3 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-04">2011-04 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A33837</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing C5164</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R214270</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99826471</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">99826471</idno>
            <idno type="VID">30874</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A33837)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 30874)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 1827:43)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>A collection of paintings and limnings, by the best masters: will be sold by auction on Friday the 1st of November, 1689. at Tom's Coffee-House, in Pope's-Head-Alley, over against the Royal-Exchange, Cornhil The sale beginning precisely at three of the clock in the afternoon. Catalogues of which are destributed by Mr. Gilliflower, in Westminster-Hall: Mr. Nott in the Pall Mall: Mr. Bently in Russel-street, Covent-Garden: Mr. Wilkinson in Fleet-street: Mr. Hargrave, at the Kings-Head, over against Furnivals-Inn in Holborn: Mr. Miller, at the Acorn, in St. Paul's Church-yard: and Mr. Crouch over against the Royal-Exchange, in Cornhil, booksellers. The conditions of sale as usual, and the time of paying and fetching away the lots so bought, to be within three days after it, at the said place.</title>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>4 p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>s.n.,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1694]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Place of publication from Wing.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of the original in the British Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Art auctions --  England --  London --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Art --  England --  Catalogs --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2009-04</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-05</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-06</date>
            <label>Lauren Proux</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-06</date>
            <label>Lauren Proux</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-09</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:30874:1"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:30874:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <p>A COLLECTION OF Paintings and Limnings, By the Beſt MASTERS: Will be Sold by AUCTION on <hi>Friday</hi> the 1ſt of <hi>November,</hi> 1689. at <hi>Tom</hi>'s Coffee-Houſe, in <hi>Pope</hi>'s <hi>Head-Alley,</hi> over againſt the <hi>Royal-Exchange, Cornhil.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>The Sale beginning preciſely at Three of the Clock in the Afternoon.</p>
            <p>Catalogues of which are deſtributed by Mr. <hi>Gilliflower,</hi> in <hi>Weſtminſter-Hall:</hi> Mr. <hi>Nott</hi> in the <hi>Pall Mall:</hi> Mr. <hi>Bently</hi> in <hi>Ruſſel-ſtreet, Covent-Garden:</hi> Mr. <hi>Wil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>kinſon</hi> in <hi>Fleet-ſtreet:</hi> Mr. <hi>Hargrave,</hi> at the Kings-Head, over againſt <hi>Furnivals-Inn</hi> in <hi>Holborn:</hi> Mr. <hi>Miller,</hi> at the Acorn, in St. <hi>Paul</hi>'s Church-yard: And Mr. <hi>Crouch</hi> over againſt the <hi>Royal-Exchange,</hi> in <hi>Cornhil,</hi> Bookſellers.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>The Conditions of Sale as uſual, and the time of paying and fetching away the Lots ſo bought, to be within three days after it, at the ſaid place.</hi>
            </p>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="collection">
            <pb n="2" facs="tcp:30874:2"/>
            <head>PAINTINGS.</head>
            <list>
               <item>1 A Wild Boar after <hi>Hondius</hi>
               </item>
               <item>2 <hi>Lot</hi> and his two Daughters, after an <hi>Italian</hi> Maſter</item>
               <item>3 Charity finely done, after an <hi>Italian</hi> Maſter</item>
               <item>4 <hi>Bacchus, Venus</hi> and <hi>Ceres,</hi> by an <hi>Italian</hi> Maſter</item>
               <item>5 <hi>Gallatea</hi> after <hi>Paul Veroneſe</hi>
               </item>
               <item>6 A Landskip after a Dutch Maſter</item>
               <item>7 A Landskip by a German Maſter</item>
               <item>8 A Droll after <hi>Brower</hi>
               </item>
               <item>9 —Another Droll by the ſame hand</item>
               <item>10 A Landskip by a German Maſter</item>
               <item>11 A Droll after <hi>Haemskirk</hi>
               </item>
               <item>12 A Landskip finely painted</item>
               <item>13 <hi>Venus</hi> and <hi>Cupid</hi> after an Italian Maſter</item>
               <item>14 Hope, Faith and Charity, after an Italian Maſter</item>
               <item>15 <hi>Bacchus</hi> and <hi>Venus,</hi> finely painted</item>
               <item>16 An Old Mans Head</item>
               <item>17 A Landskip by Maſter <hi>Knife</hi>
               </item>
               <item>18 — another, <hi>Ditto</hi>
               </item>
               <item>19 —a third Landskip, <hi>Ditto</hi>
               </item>
               <item>20 A half length of a Citizen, finely painted, by an <hi>Italian</hi> Maſter</item>
               <item>21 A Head of my Lord <hi>Strafford,</hi> after <hi>Van Dyck</hi>
               </item>
               <item>22 A piece of <hi>Abraham</hi> and <hi>Iſhmael</hi>
               </item>
               <item>23 A Story piece of <hi>Jeptha</hi> and his Daughter, by a Dutch Maſter</item>
               <item>24 A head of King <hi>James</hi> I. by an <hi>Italian</hi> Maſter</item>
               <item>25 A Mans head by the ſame hand</item>
               <item>26 A Womans head finely painted</item>
               <item>27 A half length of Prince <hi>Henry,</hi> done by the Life</item>
               <item>28 A head of a <hi>Czar</hi> of <hi>Muſcovy</hi>
               </item>
               <item>29 A half length of the Lady <hi>Herbert,</hi> by <hi>Corn. Johnſon</hi>
               </item>
               <item>30 A head of K. <hi>Charles</hi> I. ſuppoſed to be of <hi>Van Dyck</hi>
               </item>
               <item>31 His Queen after <hi>Van Dyck</hi>
               </item>
               <item>32 A half length of the Dutcheſs of <hi>Norfolk,</hi> painted by an <hi>Italian</hi>
               </item>
               <item>33 A half length of the Lady <hi>Dorſet,</hi> by the ſame</item>
               <item>34 A half length of Sir <hi>Tho. Bradbury,</hi> ſuppoſed to be of <hi>Hans Holbein</hi>
               </item>
               <item>35 A head of Mrs. <hi>Murey,</hi> after <hi>Van Dyck</hi>
               </item>
               <item>36 A little piece of Stone-work of <hi>Ferguiſon</hi>
               </item>
               <item>37 A large Hunting-piece</item>
               <item>38 A Shepherdeſs after <hi>Rubins</hi>
               </item>
               <item>39 A Kitchen-piece by a Dutch Maſter</item>
               <item>40 A Story-piece after <hi>Van Dyck</hi>
               </item>
               <item>41 A little Crucifix after <hi>Van Dyck</hi>
               </item>
               <item>42 A large piece of <hi>Jeptha</hi> and his Daughter</item>
               <item>43 A head of the Lord <hi>Dorſet</hi>
               </item>
               <item>44 A head of a Dutch Lady, by a Dutch Maſter</item>
               <item>45 A piece of Naked Men and Women, by a good hand</item>
               <item>46 A Sketch of a Cow, by the Life</item>
               <pb n="3" facs="tcp:30874:2"/>
               <item>47 A Mans head finely painted, by a great Maſter</item>
               <item>48 A Doctor of Phyſicks head finely done</item>
               <item>49 Two Globes of the Coaſtings of the World, done for Sir <hi>Francis Drake</hi>
               </item>
               <item>50 An Old Mans head</item>
               <item>51 An Old Womans head</item>
               <item>52 A piece of Fruit, by <hi>Luſt</hi>
               </item>
               <item>53 a Quack-Doctor, by a good hand</item>
               <item>54 a Landskip with Colours</item>
               <item>55 a piece of Fruit by <hi>Gilman</hi>
               </item>
               <item>56 a proſpect of a Pallace</item>
               <item>57 a Sea-piece of <hi>Vander Velde</hi>
               </item>
               <item>58 Our Saviour in the Garden, painted on Board</item>
               <item>59 a Landskip finely painted</item>
               <item>60 <hi>Mars</hi> and <hi>Venus,</hi> by a good Maſter</item>
               <item>61 a piece of Boys, by <hi>Reintly</hi>
               </item>
               <item>62 Angels appearing to the Shepherds, by the ſame hand</item>
               <item>63 a Sea-piece</item>
               <item>64 a Fruit-piece well done</item>
               <item>65 an Old head</item>
               <item>66 a piece of Flowers, curiouſly painted by <hi>Tiden</hi>
               </item>
               <item>67 an Old Womans head</item>
               <item>68 a laughing Boys head</item>
               <item>69 a Dutch Doctor, curiouſly painted by <hi>Le Creeke</hi>
               </item>
               <item>70 a <hi>Italian</hi> piece, curiouſly painted</item>
               <item>71 a curious piece of Dancers</item>
               <item>72 an head well done</item>
               <item>73 <hi>Diana</hi>'s head in Limning, with a ſilver Fillegreen frame</item>
               <item>74 <hi>Judith</hi> and <hi>Olifornes,</hi> of the ſame</item>
               <item>75 St. <hi>Jerome</hi> of the ſame</item>
               <item>76 a Piper of the ſame</item>
               <item>77 a curious Limning in a black frame</item>
               <item>78 a proſpect of a Pallace, finely painted</item>
               <item>79 a piece of Fiſh, by an <hi>Italian</hi> Maſter</item>
               <item>80 a Dutch Mountebank</item>
               <item>81 an Alchymiſt after <hi>David Teniers</hi>
               </item>
               <item>82 <hi>Jupiter</hi> and a Naked Woman after <hi>Van Dyck</hi>
               </item>
               <item>83 St. <hi>John</hi> curiouſly painted on Copper</item>
               <item>84 a Landskip finely painted on Copper</item>
               <item>85 <hi>Mary Magdalen</hi> on Copper</item>
               <item>86 a Flower-pot curiouſly painted by <hi>Crepue</hi>
               </item>
               <item>87 an Hunting-piece of <hi>Paul de Voſs</hi>
               </item>
               <item>88 a piece of Fruit</item>
               <item>89 an head well done</item>
               <item>90 —another well painted</item>
               <item>91 a piece of Flowers</item>
               <item>92 a piece of Beaſts of <hi>Van Berchem</hi>
               </item>
               <item>93 <hi>Venus</hi> and <hi>Cupid</hi>
               </item>
               <item>94 a head of K. <hi>David,</hi> by a good Maſter</item>
               <pb n="4" facs="tcp:30874:3"/>
               <item>95 a head of <hi>Bacchus</hi>
               </item>
               <item>96 a ſmall Landskip</item>
               <item>97 a curious piece of Beaſts, of <hi>Van Berchem</hi>
               </item>
               <item>98 —another piece of Beaſts, by the ſame Maſter</item>
               <item>99 <hi>Mars</hi> and <hi>Venus</hi> after <hi>Paul Veroneſe</hi>
               </item>
               <item>100 A curious head of <hi>Sophonisba</hi>
               </item>
               <item>101 Two Drolls after <hi>Brower</hi>
               </item>
               <item>102 a curious piece of Purgatory, of <hi>Brughel</hi>
               </item>
               <item>103 —another of Hell, by the ſame Maſter</item>
               <item>104 a large Landskip with figures</item>
               <item>105 a Womans head by a great Maſter</item>
               <item>106 —another by the ſame hand</item>
               <item>107 a Philoſophers head</item>
               <item>108 a School of Monkies</item>
               <item>109 King <hi>William</hi> in little</item>
               <item>110 a Fools head</item>
               <item>111 a Blackamoors head</item>
               <item>112 A piece of the Torments of Hell</item>
               <item>113 a Landskip by a great Maſter</item>
               <item>114 a Queen of <hi>Morocco</hi>
               </item>
               <item>115 <hi>Cleopatra</hi> finely done after an <hi>Italian</hi> Maſter</item>
               <item>116 a Droll piece of a Painter</item>
               <item>117 K. <hi>William</hi> three quarter Cloth</item>
               <item>118 a curious large Landskip with a Caſtle and figures in it</item>
               <item>119 another Landskip ſmaller</item>
               <item>120 a Friar Reading with an Old Woman</item>
               <item>121 a Droll after <hi>Brower</hi>
               </item>
               <item>122 a Droll after <hi>Oſtade</hi>
               </item>
               <item>123 a Uſurer after <hi>Teneirs</hi>
               </item>
               <item>124 a Droll after <hi>Oſtade</hi>
               </item>
               <item>125 a little Landskip with an Highway</item>
               <item>126 a little froſt piece</item>
               <item>127 The giving <hi>Coeſar</hi> his due after <hi>Rubens</hi>
               </item>
               <item>128 a Woman taken in Adultery after <hi>Carats,</hi> four foot half long, three foot deep</item>
               <item>129 a Virgin <hi>Mary</hi> after <hi>Carats</hi>
               </item>
               <item>130 a Landſhip with a red Cow</item>
               <item>131 a Doctor after <hi>Teneirs</hi>
               </item>
               <item>132 a little Landſhip with a Caſtle on a Rock</item>
               <item>133 a little Winter with a woman with a red Riding-hood</item>
               <item>134 a Droll of a man playing on a Kit after <hi>Teneirs</hi>
               </item>
               <item>135 a ſtory of <hi>Hero</hi> and <hi>Leander—</hi>
               </item>
               <item>136 a little Landskip with a man fiſhing</item>
               <item>137 a little froſt with a <hi>Gate</hi>
               </item>
               <item>138 a Landskip 5 foot 9 inches long, 3 foot 6 inches high</item>
               <item>139 Our Saviour Raiſing <hi>Lazarus</hi> after <hi>Rubens</hi>
               </item>
               <item>140 a Froſt with people going to Church, 4 foot 7 inches long, 2 foot 10 inches high</item>
               <item>141 a Vanity after <hi>Paul Veroneſe</hi>
               </item>
               <item>142 a Fiddler.</item>
               <item>143 a Droll.</item>
               <item>344 a Droll Chaſed in Braſs by a great Maſter in that Art</item>
               <item>345 The Froſt piece of the <hi>Thames,</hi> with a view of <hi>Lambeth-Houſe</hi>
               </item>
            </list>
            <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
            <pb facs="tcp:30874:3"/>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
